試著教我一課
耐心地，約瑟夫爵士？*
Trying to teach me a lesson in patience, Sir Joseph?
在考古學方法代表一切，我的孩子
Method is everything in archeology, my boy.
我們總是處理我們的問題
按順序查找當天。*
We always deal with our finds of the day in order.
我覺得今天挖出來的那個箱子...
Well, it seems to me that that box we dug up today,
與非常奇特
先生，那邊，*
with the very peculiar gentleman, over there,
是過去的兩個月以來，唯一的發現...
is the only find we've made in the past two months
這將為這次探險 獲得大英博物館的頒獎
that'll bring this expedition any medals from the British Museum.
我們來埃及挖掘，不是為了得獎牌
We didn't come to dig in Egypt for medals.
從中學到了更多
從研究這些陶器碎片獲取學問*
Much more is learned from studying bits of broken pottery
而非而不是
所有聳人聽聞的發現。*
than from all the sensational finds.
我們的工作是去增進人類對古代的了解
Our job is to increase the sum of human knowledge of the past,
不是為了滿足我們自己的好奇心
not to satisfy our own curiosity.
約瑟夫爵士，你說的很有道理，但畢竟我們是人
That's all very true, Sir Joseph, but after all, we're human.
有此種發現...你怎麼還能等？
And a find like this... Well, how can you wait?
這是你第一次來，我到此工作已經10年了
This is your first trip. I've been out here 10 years,
對那個木乃伊，我比你還要好奇...
and I'm more curious about that mummy than you are,
甚至那個箱子也是
and even more about that box.
惠普。是？
Whemple. Yes?
內臟未被移除
The viscera were not removed.
沒發現屍體防腐工作者常見的刀痕
The usual scar made by the embalmer's knife is not there.
我看也是，穆勒
I guessed as much, Muller.
在拍照的時候，我很仔細看過他了
I had a good look at him when I photographed him.
從未見過這樣的木乃伊
Never saw a mummy like that.
我想，應該沒任何人見過
Neither, I imagine, has anyone else.
看起來似乎他死於某種慘絕人寰的方式
Looks as though he died in some sensationally unpleasant manner.
扭曲的肌肉顯示他在繃帶裡掙扎
The contorted muscles show that he struggled in the bandages.
被活埋了
Buried alive.
“印和闐”
"Imhotep,"
“卡納克太陽神殿的大祭司“
"High Priest of the Temple of the Sun at Karnak."
可憐的老傢伙
Poor old fellow.
到底做了什麼，才會得到這種逞罰？
Now, what could you have done to make them treat you like that?
叛國罪被處決，我想
An execution for treason, I suppose.
比較像是褻瀆，看
Sacrilege, more likely. Look.
在通往冥界的旅途中，用來保護靈魂的符咒...
The sacred spells which protect the soul in its journey to the underworld
從棺材裡削掉了
have been chipped off of the coffin.
所以印和闐不但在人間被判死刑，在陰間也是
So Imhotep was sentenced to death not only in this world, but in the next.
也許他跟神殿的女祭司，過得太歡樂了
Maybe he got too gay with the vestal virgins in the temple.
有可能
Possibly.
卡納克神殿的女祭司...
The priestesses of the Temple of Karnak
是統治者法老的女兒們
were the daughters of the reigning pharaohs.
他們是伊希斯女神的神聖處女
They were the sacred virgins of Isis.
跟他一起陪葬的箱子裡，也許有答案
Maybe the answer's in that box we found buried with him.
我知道在打開箱子之前，我不可能得到解答
I see I shall get no more work out of you until after it's open.
來吧。讓我們去拿箱子
Come on. Let's have the box up there.
木頭腐朽至此，一碰就粉碎了
The Wood's so rotten, it'll fall apart at a touch.
不管是什麼，還真重的要命
Whatever it is, it's terribly heavy.
金屬，看起來像銅
Metal. Looks like copper.
這是黃金
It's gold.
我說！看這裡
I say! Look here.
阿蒙諾菲斯法老 完整的印章
The unbroken seals of the Pharaoh Amenophis.
一些神殿的寶藏
Some temple treasure.
“死亡，永恆的懲罰...”
"Death, eternal punishment"
“不論是誰...”
"for anyone"
“只要他打開這個棺材...”
"who opens this casket,"
“奉阿蒙-拉之名--“
"in the name of Amon-Ra,"
“眾神之王”
"the King of the Gods."
我的媽呀！好可怕的詛咒！
Good heavens! What a terrible curse!
讓我們看看裡面有什麼。等等！
Well, let's see what's inside. Wait!
你已經念了咒文
You have read the curse.
我們知道你在玄學方面學有專精，穆勒...
We recognize your mastery of the occult sciences, Muller,
但我不能讓你的信仰來干擾我的工作
but I can't permit your beliefs to interfere with my work.
那今天下午為什麼叫我來？
Then why did you send for me this afternoon?
作為朋友和專家
As a friend and an expert.
因為這項發現很獨特，我想徵求你的意見
Because I saw this find was unique, and I wanted your opinion on it.
你如此做，頗符合天意
It is providential that you did.
來吧，穆勒博士。當然有幾個
在地球上千年*
Come, Dr. Muller. Surely a few thousand years in the earth
會採取mumbo-jumbo
任何舊的詛咒。*
would take the mumbo-jumbo off any old curse.
我不能在一個男孩面前說
I cannot speak before a boy.
出去埃及的星空下
Come out under the stars of Egypt.
不要碰那個棺材
Do not touch that casket.
繼續做你的編目，我們稍後會打開
Go on with your cataloging. We'll open it later.
你不用費心說服我，不要去檢查...
You needn't think you can persuade me not to examine
我在此地全部的經歷裡面 最精彩的發現
the most wonderful find of my whole experience out here.
關於這個傳說，如果你是對的...
If you're right about the legend,
那這個棺材可能有智慧之神的捲軸
then this casket may contain the Scroll of Thoth
那是這個神殿的聖中之聖
from the holy of holies in the temple.
我迫不及待想回去找出來
And I can hardly wait to get back to find out.
埃及眾神仍然活躍在這些山區，在他們傾頹的神殿中
The gods of Egypt still live in these hills, in their ruined temples.
古代符咒雖減弱，但是其中一些仍有法力...
The ancient spells are weaker, but some of them are still potent,
我相信你的棚屋裡有智慧之神的捲軸...
and I believe that you have in your hut the Scroll of Thoth itself,
其中包含了偉大的咒語...
伊希斯女神持此咒讓俄西里斯死而復生
which contains the great spell by which Isis raised Osiris from the dead.
放回去吧。埋回原來的發現之處
Put it back. Bury it where you found it.
你既已念了咒文，你膽敢違逆嗎？
You have read the curse. You dare defy it?
為了科學的利益，即使我相信詛咒...
In the interest of science, even if I believed in the curse,
也要繼續替博物館 完我的工作
I'd go on with my work for the museum.
跟我一起回去，我們一起來檢查這個偉大的發現
Come back with me, and we'll examine this great find together.
在我目睹之下，無法容忍此種褻瀆神靈的行為
I cannot condone an act of sacrilege with my presence.
怎麼了，老兄？這是什麼？
What's the matter, man? For heaven's sake, what is it?
他...他走了一會兒
He... He went for a little walk.
你應該看看他的臉
You should have seen his face.
總算有點刺激的事來了
Here's something to break the monotony.
有一位訪客從尼羅河走上小路了
There's a visitor coming up the trail from the Nile.
膚色？國籍？
Color? Nationality?
那麼刺眼，哪看得清楚？
How could I see in that glare?
惠普，我們回到倫敦去吧
Well, Whemple, back we go to London.
我們看起來有多蠢
And what fools we look.
在該死的沙漠一個洞接一個洞的挖，錢都白花了
Money wasted. Hole after hole dug in this blasted desert.
幾顆珠子，幾個破鍋子
A few beads, a few broken pots.
幹這一行，不是辛苦工作就行的
A man needs more than hard work for this game.
他需要天賦，需要運氣，就像你父親一樣
He needs flair. He needs luck, like your father.
以前他來這裡的時候，還沒那麼多競爭者
In the days when he used to come out here, there wasn't so much competition.
只要他一來，就有所斬獲
When he did, he found things.
曾經，10年前吧，他發現太多東西了
And once, 10 years ago, he found too much.
是10年前的事嗎？
Was it 10 years ago?
怪事，他一起鬼混的那個牛津的年輕小夥子
Queer story, that young Oxford chap he had with him going mad.
-知道我認為它是什麼嗎？   -不，是什麼？
-You know what I think it was?  -No. What?
我覺得他瘋了，很無聊
超越人類的耐力
I think he went crazy, bored beyond human endurance,
亂搞
這沙子和這些岩石。
messing around in this sand and these rocks.
你父親找到了他的時候，他笑個不停
He was laughing when your father found him.
他笑到死，穿著緊身夾克
He died laughing, in a straitjacket.
你父親從沒解釋過
Your father never explained.
但當時英格蘭已研發出最好的挖掘機...
But when the best excavator England has turned out,
一個熱愛埃及的人，說他永遠不會回這裡...
a man who loved Egypt, said he'd never come back here,
這一定有某些意義
that meant something.
進來吧
Come in.
你弄壞了你的營地，皮爾森教授？
You break your season's camp, Professor Pearson?
你的同事們回倫敦了？
Your colleagues have returned to London?
是。惠普和我留了下來清理
Yes. Whemple and I stayed behind to clear up.
你們的探險尚未成功
Your expedition has not been a success.
幾乎沒有。這些是本季的發現
Scarcely. Here are the season's finds.
容我向您展示自圖坦卡蒙以來最轟動發現
Permit me to present you with the most sensational find since that of Tutankhamen.
沒見過你這麼興奮，可以問為什麼嗎？
This is very sporting of you. May I ask why?
我們埃及人不被允許去挖掘我們祖先的遺骸
We Egyptians are not permitted to dig up our ancient dead.
只有外國的博物館
Only foreign museums.
那這是什麼？
Well, what's this?
安克蘇娜姆公主陪葬品的一部分...，
Part of the funerary equipment of the Princess Anck-es-en-Amon,
偉大的阿蒙諾菲斯的女兒
daughter of Amenophis the Magnificent.
是。這是她的名字
Yes. It's her name.
在距離我們不到100碼的地方發現的
I found that not 100 yards from where we are.
你是說，你認為她的墳墓在那裡？
You mean, you think her tomb is there?
我會告訴你在哪裡挖的
I will show you where to dig.
我覺得你非常好心，你是...
I'm sure it's very good of you, Mr...
我沒聽清楚你的名字
I didn't catch your name.
阿德斯.貝
Ardeth Bay.
只有旁證，證據不足，也許...
Circumstantial evidence. Not very strong, perhaps,
但如果把Kerna那群挖工調來這裡工作...
but if we put that gang of diggers from Kerna on the job,
如果這裡有什麼，兩天內就知分曉
we can tell in two days if there's anything here.
一天內，教授
In one day, Professor.
小心階梯！
It's a step!
他說的沒錯
He was right.
總之，我們發現一些東西
Anyhow, we found something.
安克蘇娜姆的名字
The name of Anck-es-en-Amon.
我們發電報給你在倫敦的父親
We will cable your father in London.
他會趕來跟我們一起研究這個偉大的發現
He must be here when we examine this great find.
七個豺狼的印章
The seal of the seven jackals.
而且是完整的
And it's unbroken.
皇家墓地的祭司密封這扇門之後，就沒人進入過
No one has entered this door since the priests of the royal necropolis sealed it.
三千七百年前
3,700 years ago.
世界上還有這種景觀嗎，海倫？
Is there a view like this in all the world, Helen?
真正的埃及
The real Egypt.
我們真的到了驚人的，現代的開羅？
Are we really in this dreadful, modern Cairo?
你的心思已遠離舞會，和這些漂亮的英國男孩
Your thoughts are far away from the dance and these nice English boys, my dear.
才不是，我在享受這段美好的時光
Not really. I'm having a lovely time.
-我很感激。     -但為什麼？
-I'm so grateful.     -But why?
當然是因為你把我留下來陪你
For your keeping me here with you, of course.
所以我就不用到燠熱蠻荒的蘇丹 去找神父
So I don't have to go up to Father in that beastly hot Sudan.
我得感激我最有趣的病人
It's I who am grateful, my most interesting patient.
知道那是誰嗎？
Know who that is?
-維也納的穆勒   -真的？
-Muller of Vienna.    -Really?
總是來這裡過冬，他是埃及神秘學的權威
Always spends his winters here. Authority on the Egyptian occult.
是的，但那女孩
Yes, but the girl.
海倫.格羅夫納
Helen Grosvenor.
她父親是蘇丹總督，自然是英國人了
Her father's Governor of the Sudan. English, of course.
她母親是埃及人。有些老家族的族譜有一英里長
Her mother, Egyptian. Some old family with a tree a mile long.
她跟穆勒博士夫婦住在這裡
She's staying here with Dr. and Mrs. Muller.
對不起，先生。我們的打烊鈴響了
Pardon me, sir. Our closing bell has rung.
我沒注意到時間
I did not notice the time.
我正在跟約瑟夫.惠普爵士談話？
I am addressing Sir Joseph Whemple?
是
Yes.
我是阿德斯.貝 Bay
I am Ardeth Bay.
確實！
Indeed!
我們能欣賞這個展覽全都要感謝你
Why, we have you to thank that we have this exhibit here at all.
為了閣下光臨，博物館應該整夜開放
The museum should be kept open all night in your honor.
你想下來我的辦公室嗎？我工作到很晚
Won't you come down to my office? I'm working here late.
請你原諒。我不喜歡被碰觸
Your pardon. I dislike to be touched.
東方人的偏見
An Eastern prejudice.
你不坐下嗎？
Won't you sit down?
你認識我的兒子
You know my son.
阿德斯.貝。打開墓室的時候，你跑去哪兒了？
Ardeth Bay. Where did you disappear to when we opened the tomb?
我回到了開羅
I returned to Cairo.
但...但現在我不能叨擾你
But... But now I must not detain you.
但我必須再見到你。你...必須來我家
But I must see you again. You... You must come to my house.
很遺憾我太忙了，無法接受邀請
I regret I am too occupied to accept invitations.
他是個怪人
He's a strange one.
但至少你要感謝那個人
But you might at least have thanked the man.
他很盡責去尋找公主
He was responsible for finding the princess.
是啊。我倒希望他沒這麼盡心
Yes. I rather wish he hadn't been.
我認為這是個詭計，開羅博物館保留我們所發現的一切
I think it's a dirty trick, this Cairo Museum keeping everything we've found.
那是合同
That was the contract.
大英博物館為此工作是基於科學因素，而非戰利品
The British Museum works for the cause of science, not for loot.
安克蘇娜姆
Anck-es-en-Amon.
有什麼事嗎？
Is anything the matter?
安克蘇娜姆
Anck-es-en-Amon.
小姐，你想去哪裡？
Where do you want to go, miss?
古物博物館
Le Musee des Antiquites.
印和闐
Imhotep.
安克蘇娜姆。安克蘇娜姆
Anck-es-en-Amon. Anck-es-en-Amon.
印和闐
Imhotep.
我必須進去
I must get in.
安克蘇娜姆
Anck-es-en-Amon.
我必須
I must.
夜間是關閉的，每個人都回家了
It's closed for the night. Everybody's gone home.
我必須進去
I must get in.
印和闐 印和闐
Imhotep. Imhotep.
印和闐
Imhotep.
她在說什麼？
What's she saying?
那是什麼語言？
What language is that?
古埃及的語言，在地球上消失2000年了
The language of Ancient Egypt, not heard on this earth for 2,000 years.
而那個名字，特洛伊戰爭之前就不曾再提及
And the name of a man unspoken since before the siege of Troy.
你的主人在家嗎？
Is your master at home?
是的，大人
Yes, efendi.
告訴他，穆勒博士迫切地想見他
Tell him Dr. Muller wishes to see him, urgently.
我怎麼到這裡了？
How did I get here?
我們把你帶來的，父親和我
We brought you here. Father and I.
你昏過去了
You fainted.
但你怎麼會猜到她在這兒？
But how did you guess she was here?
我發現她在旅館 搭計程車去博物館
I discovered that she took a taxi from the hotel to the museum.
我到了那兒，守門的說她搭你的車離開了
I went there. The watchman said she had left in your car.
帶走她之前，我必須告訴你她剛說的話
Before you take her away, I must talk to you about something she said just now.
哦，穆勒博士
Oh, Dr. Muller.
你在這兒啊，親愛的
So, here you are, my dear.
你應該介紹過自己了
I suppose you introduced yourself.
沒有？
No?
海倫.格羅夫納小姐；約瑟夫·惠普爵士，法蘭克·惠普
Miss Helen Grosvenor, my old friend Sir Joseph Whemple, Frank Whemple.
在這些奇特的情況，這似乎太正式了
This seems so formal under these peculiar circumstances.
如果你沒事的話，我們回去旅館*
And now, if you're all right again, back we go to the hotel.
我...我認為她應該休息幾分鐘
I... I think she ought to rest a few minutes.
法蘭克，你會做的嗎？*
Frank, will you make yourself agreeable?
那...
Well...
我在哪裡暈倒的，惠普先生？
Where was I when I fainted, Mr. Whemple?
哦，在博物館外面
Oh, outside the museum.
我在那做什麼？
What was I doing there?
我不可能知道，我會嗎？
Well, I wouldn't know that, would I?
不，我不認為你知道
No, I don't suppose you would.
但願我知道，你看，我在等...
I wish I did. You see, I was waiting...
我們別談這件事
Let's not talk about it.
喔，對
Oh, right.
你有埃及人血統，不是嗎？
You're partly Egyptian, aren't you?
是。你怎麼測猜到的？
Yes. How did you guess that?
哦，我不知道。你的一些氣質吧
Oh, I don't know. Just something about you.
如果在那裡遇到你，我會更喜歡埃及，但我沒那運氣
You know, I'd have liked Egypt better if I'd met you there, but no such luck.
困在沙漠裡兩個月，又熱得要命！
Stuck in the desert for two months, and was it hot!
那個墳墓！
That tomb!
什麼墳墓？
What tomb?
你一定讀過公主的故事
Surely you read about the princess.
-所以你看過了    -是
-So you did that.    -Yes.
14的階梯下，那完整的印章令人驚心
The 14 steps down and the unbroken seals were thrilling.
但當我們去處理她所有的衣物、珠寶和如廁用品...
But when we came to handle all her clothes and her jewels and her toilet things...
你知道，他們埋葬了他們生前的所有器物
You know, they buried everything with them that they used in life.
當我們去解開那女孩...
Well, when we came to unwrap the girl herself...
你怎能這樣做？
How could you do that?
不得不。科學嘛，你知道的
Had to. Science, you know.
在我們處理她的東西之後，我覺得好像認識她
Well, after we'd worked among her things, I felt as if I'd known her.
當我們解開了繃帶，我看到了她的臉...
And when we got the wrappings off, and I saw her face...
你會認為我好傻，但我好像愛上她了
You'll think me silly, but I sort of fell in love with her.
你得挖開墳墓去找一個心上人嗎？
Do you have to open graves to find girls to fall in love with?
嘿！
I say!
現在我知道了你是怎麼回事
Now I know what it is about you.
她的頭有一些東西...
There was something about her head...
我從未提及這個名字...
I had never mentioned the name,
然而我聽到格羅夫納小姐...
用古埃及語，喃喃說著印和闐的事
yet I heard Miss Grosvenor mutter, in ancient Egyptian, something about Imhotep.
印和闐？
Imhotep?
那時阿德斯在博物館幹什麼？
What was this Ardeth doing in the museum?
看著木乃伊，就在閉館的時後
Looking at the mummy, just at closing time.
你好
Hello.
什麼？
What?
來
Come.
一名博物館警衛被發現死在公主的房間
A museum guard found dead in the room of the princess.
他因驚嚇而死
So he died of shock.
在死去的警衛手中，發現了這個，約瑟夫爵士
We find this in dead guard's hand, Sir Joseph.
可能小偷想偷，但警衛拿走了，小偷就殺了他
Probably thief try to steal it. Guard take it away, thief kill him.
死因，我一無所獲
The cause of death, I not find nothing.
看起來像是盜竊未遂，但沒任何東西失竊
Looks like an attempted theft, but nothing stolen here could be disposed of.
什麼是文件？
What is the document?
我把它放在這裡，你會安心一些
Let me put this here. You'll be more comfortable.
謝謝
Thanks.
你真的想知道我為什麼沒帶你去醫院？
You really want to know why I didn't take you to the hospital?
因為當我把你抱在懷中...
Because when I held you in my arms...
你不要那麼癡情好嗎？*
Hadn't you better not commit yourself?
女孩在月光下癱倒在你腳下，有哪個男人能抗拒？
What girl could fail to make a conquest who collapsed at a man's feet in the moonlight?
我們彼此認識的時間這麼短，我知道這很荒謬
Oh, I know it seems absurd when we've known each other such a short time,
但我是認真的
but I'm serious.
你不覺得這一個晚上我驚嚇已經過多了...
Don't you think I've had enough excitement for one evening,
還要添加一個陌生人對我示愛？
without the additional thrill of a strange man making love to me?
但我從來沒有像現在這麼認真過
But I've never been serious about this sort of thing before.
現在，看看這裡
Now, look here.
你可以叫我去死，但你不能嘲笑我
You can tell me to go to the devil, but you can't laugh at me.
詛咒襲擊了她，現在經由她，它將攻擊我兒子
The curse has struck her, and now, through her, it will strike my son.
安靜
Quiet.
法蘭克，你去你父親的書房好嗎？
Frank, will you come to your father's study?
海倫，我會親自送你回家
Helen, I shall take you home presently.
我馬上就回來
I'll be back in a minute.
印和闐還活著...
Imhotep was alive
當那個在博物館的木乃伊是神殿的女祭司
when that mummy in the museum was a vestal virgin in the temple.
三千七百年前！現在和我們有什麼關係？
Thirty-seven hundred years ago! What's that got to do with us, now?
你的助手，他瘋狂的死了...
Your assistant, who went insane and died,
你可能已經做過了，如果你看到他所看到的...*
as you might have done if you'd seen what he saw,
做了該捲軸一部分的轉譯*
made a transcription of part of that scroll.
是。仍然在我手上
Yes. I have it still.
你似乎認為這東西，什麼妖魔鬼怪在裡面
You seem to think this thing has all the devils of Hell in it.
為什麼不燒了它，一了百了？
Why not burn it and be done with it?
一個優秀的建議
An excellent suggestion.
印和闐的木乃伊後來怎樣了？
What became of the mummy of Imhotep?
被人偷走了
Somebody stole it.
看這裡，穆勒博士。格羅夫納小姐怎麼了？
Look here, Dr. Muller. What's the matter with Miss Grosvenor?
你仍然認為木乃伊被偷了，約瑟夫爵士？
You still think that that mummy was stolen, Sir Joseph?
是的，我...
Yes, I...
哦，我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
萬分抱歉，我是阿德斯.貝
A thousand pardons. I am Ardeth Bay.
我是海倫.格羅夫納
I'm Helen Grosvenor.
有人叫我去見約瑟夫爵士
I called to see Sir Joseph.
他正在書房
He's in the study.
會議嗎？也許我等一會兒
A conference? If I might perhaps wait.
是。當然
Yes. Of course.
我們以前見過嗎，格羅夫納小姐？
Have we not met before, Miss Grosvenor?
不，我不這麼認為
No, I don't think so.
我不認為和你見面後會忘了你，阿德斯.貝
I don't think one would forget meeting you, Ardeth Bay.
那是我弄錯了
Then I am mistaken.
但你有我們的血統
But you are of our blood.
至於那個，我沒有弄錯
As to that, I am not mistaken.
是
Yes.
我母親是埃及人
My mother was Egyptian.
你必須燒掉智慧之神的捲軸
You must burn the Scroll of Thoth.
我告訴你，這是博物館的財產，不是我的
I tell you, it's the museum's property, not mine.
外面跟著格羅夫納小姐的是誰？
Who's out there with Miss Grosvenor?
阿德斯.貝
Ardeth Bay.
他為捲軸而來
He's come for the scroll.
阿德斯.貝，穆勒博士
Ardeth Bay, Dr. Muller.
我接受你的邀請，但我發現沒有帶著書的單身學生
I accept your invitation, but I find no solitary student with his books.
我擔心我的訪問不洽當
I fear my visit is inopportune.
相反的，我們剛談及...
On the contrary, we were just talking about...
我？
Me?
你的祖國埃及
Your native Egypt.
你認識格羅夫納小姐嗎？
You know Miss Grosvenor?
阿德斯.貝自我介紹了
Ardeth Bay introduced himself.
你不坐嗎？
Won't you be seated?
約瑟夫爵士剛在納悶 你怎麼知道...
Sir Joseph was just wondering how you knew
安克蘇娜姆公主的陵墓被隱藏在何處
where the tomb of the Princess Anck-es-en-Amon was hidden.
部分推論，部分是機運
Partly inference, partly chance.
約瑟夫爵士，你似乎很不安
Sir Joseph, you seem disturbed.
是。你離開博物館後，有一場悲劇
Yes. A tragedy at the museum after you left.
悲劇？
Tragedy?
我當時在現場？
When I was there?
當時你在那裡，格羅夫納小姐？
When you were there, Miss Grosvenor?
是的。閉館之後我想進去時，他們告訴我的
Yes. They told me I went there and tried to get in after it was closed.
我不記得了，但...
I don't remember, but...
海倫，已經很晚了
Helen, it is very late.
法蘭克，請你帶海倫回旅館好嗎？
Frank, will you please see Helen back to the hotel?
當然，如果格羅夫納小姐允許
Certainly, if Miss Grosvenor will let me.
但我不想去
But I don't want to go.
發生了這些事，你非常需要休息
After what happened, you need rest badly.
但我不要
But I don't.
我是累了，但我...
I was tired, but I...
我不曾感到這麼活躍過
Why, I've never felt so alive before.
作為你的醫生，我必須命令你去
Then as your doctor, I must order you to go.
我又不是孩子
I'm not a child.
是。請，來。
Yes. Please, come.
那...阿德斯.貝，再見
Then, Ardeth Bay, au revoir.
但我們一定要再次會面
But we must see each other again.
我會很榮幸的
I shall be honored.
不尋常的罪行
An unusual crime.
一名警衛被一名男子殺死，兇手給博物館留下禮物
A guard killed by a man who left a gift to the museum.
禮物？
A gift?
一個捲軸
A scroll.
當它首次被發現時，有一部分被轉譯了
Part of which was transcribed when it was first found.
這是譯本
Here is the transcription.
時間這麼久遠，我看不懂寫什麼
I cannot read the writing of a period so remote.
但你念出了那片陶器上，安克蘇娜姆的名字
But you read the name of Anck-es-en-Amon on that piece of pottery.
這是第18王朝
That was of the 18th Dynasty.
這些是王朝統治前的象形文字
These are Predynastic ideographs.
這捲軸翻自10年前被盜走的手抄本...*
The scroll from which this was copied was stolen 10 years ago,
和大祭司印和闐的木乃伊放在一起
together with the mummy of the High Priest Imhotep.
甚為有趣
Most interesting.
我可以看看那捲軸，約瑟夫爵士？
May I see that scroll, Sir Joseph?
我們把它留在博物館了
We left it at the museum.
這樣啊
So.
我有別樣東西躍給你看，一張照片
I have something else to show you. A photograph.
為什麼要向我展示這些？
Why do you show all this to me?
木乃伊不是被偷走的，你覺得這能想像嗎？
Do you think it conceivable that the mummy was not stolen,
但恢復了生活的外表***
通過Scroll的拼寫...
but restored to a semblance of life by the spell from the Scroll of...
那捲軸是我的財產。
我是從經銷商處買的。
That scroll is my property.
I bought it from a dealer.
它就在這所房子裡。
我假設在那個房間裡。
It is here in this house.
I presume in that room.
我們已經預見到了這一點。
We had foreseen this.
捲軸安全，
The scroll is in safe hands,
它將在一分鐘內被銷毀
眾所周知，傷害已經到來。
and will be destroyed the minute it
is known that harm has come to us.
你研究過我們的古代藝術，和
你知道你不能傷害我。
You have studied our ancient arts, and
you know that you cannot harm me.
你也知道你必須
將滾動歸還給我或死去。
You also know that you must
return that scroll to me or die.
現在告訴那個弱小的傻瓜
滾動，無論在哪裡，
Now tell that weak fool to get
that scroll, wherever it is,
並把它交給
他的努比亞僕人。
and hand it to
his Nubian servant.
努比亞人！
The Nubian!
古老的血統。
The ancient blood.
所以你創造了他
你的奴隸。
So you have made him
your slave.
如果我可以抓住你，
If I could get my hands on you,
我打破你的
肉乾成碎。
I'd break your
dried flesh to pieces.
但是你的力量太強了。
But your power is too strong.
這是邪惡的力量
一直在攻擊她。
This is the evil force that
has been attacking her.
男人，燒了捲軸。
燒掉它吧！
Burn the scroll, man.
Burn it!
這是通過你
恐怖的存在。
It was through you this
horror came into existence.
這是真的。
It's true.
知道，你父親摧毀了捲軸
這會讓他失去生命。
Your father destroyed the scroll, knowing
that it would cost him his life.
那是什麼？
What's that?
伊希斯，埃及人
生命的象徵。
Isis, the Egyptian
symbol of life.
我的意思是你的父親
I meant it for your father.
這可能有多大的好處
魅力已經完成了他？
What good could that old
charm have done him?
我告訴你，醫生說是的
一例心臟衰竭。
I tell you, the doctors say it's
a plain case of heart failure.
努比亞人失?了。
The Nubian is missing.
他是個老僕人。他是
嚇壞了，但他會回來的。
He's an old servant. He was
frightened, but he'll be back.
不要試圖讓我相信這一點
阿德斯.貝的傢伙是一個木乃伊來生活。
Don't try and make me believe that this
Ardeth fellow is a mummy come to life.
這就是那個想法和恐怖
它殺了我父親
It was that idea and the horror
of it that killed my father.
博物館警衛死了
也是自然原因。
The museum guard died
of natural causes, too.
法蘭克，我需要你的幫助。
Frank, I need your help.
我看到了你對我的病人的吸引力
昨晚，她和你。
I saw your attraction to my patient
last night, and hers to you.
她對我？你呢
真的這麼認為？
Hers to me? Do you
really think so?
我歡迎它。
And I welcomed it.
但你認為嗎？
我有機會嗎？
But do you think
I have a chance?
因為我想
她是最...
'Cause I think
she's the most...
但這太可怕了
在這樣的時間。
But this is terrible
at a time like this.
法蘭克，我很害怕。你會
現在和我一起去找她？
Frank, I'm afraid. Will you
go with me to her now?
是。
Yes.
然後先給她打電話
不要離開旅館。
Then telephone her first
not to leave the hotel.
9-5-9-0.
不，我不會出去。
No, I'm not going out.
是的，我保證會等
直到你到這兒
Yes, I promise to wait
until you get here.
再見。
Goodbye.
而且我非常抱歉。
And I'm so dreadfully sorry.
你懂...
You know...
你在做什麼，博士？
What were you doing, Doctor?
你父親沒有燒掉Scroll
透特那個生物現在擁有它。
Your father did not burn the Scroll
of Thoth. That creature has it now.
但是壁爐裡的灰燼。
But the ashes in the fireplace.
他們是報紙。
捲軸是紙莎草紙。
They were newspaper.
The scroll is papyrus.
然後是謀殺。
努比亞人。
Then it was murder.
The Nubian.
戴在脖子上。
Wear this around your neck.
為什麼？
Why?
當我們對抗這個生物時，
When we fight this creature,
我們必須要求保護
它無視的舊勢力。
we must ask protection from the
forces of old that it defied.
我會把它交給海倫。她
需要保護的人。
I'll give it to Helen. She's
the one that needs protection.
不，她的生活不是
在危險之中。這是她的靈魂。
No. Her life is not
in danger. It is her soul.
應該愛你來找她，
他會試圖摧毀你。
Should love for you come to her,
he will try to destroy you.
那個護身符，
埃及人相信，
That amulet, the
Egyptians believe,
是邪惡派遣的魅力
比如擊倒了你的父親。
was a charm against evil sendings
such as struck down your father.
你的狗嚇壞了。
我的僕人會看見他。
Your dog is frightened.
My servant will see to him.
坐下，格羅夫納小姐。
Sit down, Miss Grosvenor.
古埃及。
Ancient Egypt.
什麼都不現代。
Nothing modern.
多麼奇怪的香。
What a strange incense.
你不熟悉嗎？
Is it not familiar to you?
沒有。
我們的祖先使用它。
No.
Our forefathers used it.
你和我的。
Yours and mine.
你不會記得的
我現在告訴你的是什麼
You will not remember
what I show you now,
然而我會醒來
愛的回憶
and yet I shall awaken
memories of love
和犯罪和死亡
and crime and death.
我跪在死亡床上。
I knelt by the bed of death.
你父親最後的告別。
Thy father's last farewell.
我知道Thoth捲軸
可以讓你恢復活力。
I knew the Scroll of Thoth
could bring thee back to life.
我敢於眾神的憤怒
偷了它。
I dared the gods' anger
and stole it.
我偷回了你的墳墓
讓你恢復活力。
I stole back to thy tomb
to bring thee back to life.
我咒罵這個咒語
那引起了死人，
I murmured the spell
that raises the dead,
但是他們突然襲擊了我
but they broke in upon me
發現我在做
一個不聖潔的東西。
and found me doing
an unholy thing.
你父親譴責我
無名的死亡。
Thy father condemned me
to the nameless death.
他訂購的捲軸
和我一起埋葬，
The scroll he ordered
buried with me,
沒有這樣的褻瀆
可能會再次羞辱埃及。
that no such sacrilege
might disgrace Egypt again.
無名的墳墓。
A nameless grave.
奴隸被殺了
所以沒有人應該知道。
The slaves were killed
so that none should know.
殺死他們的士兵
也被殺了，
The soldiers who killed them
were also slain,
所以沒有朋友可以悄悄地走向
沙漠與葬禮
so no friend could creep to the
desert with funeral offerings
因為我的譴責精神。
for my condemned spirit.
安克蘇娜姆
Anck-es-en-Amon.
我的愛情持續了很長時間
比我們眾神的寺廟。
My love has lasted longer
than the temples of our gods.
沒有人受苦
就像我為你做的那樣。
No man ever suffered
as I did for you.
但其餘的你可能不知道。
But the rest you may not know.
直到你即將通過
恐怖和勝利的偉大夜晚，
Not until you are about to pass through
the great night of terror and triumph,
直到你準備面對時刻
恐懼永恆的愛情。
until you are ready to face moments
of horror for an eternity of love.
直到我送回你的精神
Until I send back your spirit
已經徘徊過
許多形式和許多年齡。
that has wandered through so
many forms and so many ages.
但在那之前，Bast必須
再次發死。
But before then, Bast must
again send forth death.
那個愛的男孩死了
正在爬進你的心裡。
Death to that boy for whom love
is creeping into your heart.
愛會保持
你是我自己。
Love that would keep
you from myself.
愛可能會帶來疾病
甚至死亡給你。
Love that might bring sickness
and even death to you.
甦醒。
Awake.
我睡著了嗎？
Have I been asleep?
我有奇怪的夢想。
I had strange dreams.
古代夢想
埃及，我想。
Dreams of Ancient
Egypt, I think.
有人
跟你在一起吧。
There was someone
like you in them.
我的游泳池有時會受到困擾。
My pool is sometimes troubled.
人們看到了奇怪的幻想
水，但他們像夢一樣經過。
One sees strange fantasies in the
water, but they pass like dreams.
我的狗！鎢！
鎢！
My dog! Wolfram!
Wolfram!
他在哪裡？
Where is he?
海倫。
Helen.
海倫，你去過哪裡？
Helen, where have you been?
我們一直很擔心。
我們到處追捕。
We've been so worried.
We've hunted everywhere.
又在博物館？
是。
In the museum again?
Yes.
穆勒下來了
阿拉伯區現在。
Muller's down in
the Arab quarter now.
好吧，如果我必須給一個
解釋，這裡很悶。
Well, if I must give an
explanation, it was stuffy in here.
我不能閉嘴
每時每刻。
I can't be shut up
all the time.
此外，我不喜歡這種感覺
我一直在被關注。
Besides, I don't like the feeling
that I'm always being watched.
我和我一起帶了狗。
I took the dog with me.
好吧，狗在哪裡？
Well, where is the dog?
他...他死了。
He's... He's dead.
但是怎麼樣？
But how?
我不知道
I don't know.
哪裡？
Where?
我不記得了。
I don't remember.
但我現在可以看到它，站在那裡
可憐的沃爾夫勒姆回來了，一隻白色的貓。
But I can see it now, standing on
poor Wolfram's back, a white cat.
一隻白貓？
A white cat?
貓女神，巴斯特。
The cat goddess, Bast.
是的，有
巴斯特的雕像。
Yes, there was
a statue of Bast.
邪惡女神的送女神！
The goddess of evil sendings!
發生了什麼事？
試著記住，海倫。
Just what happened?
Try to remember, Helen.
我不想記得。
I don't want to remember.
此外，我沒有看到
這是你的任何事情。
Besides, I don't see
that it's any affair of yours.
哦，但確實如此。我們知道
你在阿德斯.貝 Bay。
Oh, but it is. We know that
you were with Ardeth Bay.
哦，海倫。
Oh, Helen.
海倫，我愛你。我嘗試著
幫助你並保護你。
Helen, I love you. I'm trying
to help you and protect you.
我們都是。
別再讓我走了。
We all are.
Don't let me go again.
我會試圖逃脫，但你不能讓
我，無論我做什麼或我說什麼。
I'll try to get away, but you mustn't let
me, no matter what I do or what I say.
那裡有我的死亡和生命
我內心的其他東西不是我。
There's death there for me, and life for
something else inside me that isn't me.
但它也活著，
並為生命而戰。
But it's alive, too,
and fighting for life.
法蘭克，救我脫離它。
救救我。
Save me from it, Frank.
Save me.
哦，一切都好
會沒事的。
Oh, everything's
going to be all right.
既然你已經尋求幫助了
我永遠不會讓你孤單。
Now that you've asked for help,
I'll never leave you alone.
我會讓穆勒太太跟你一起來，
我會呆在這裡，直到醫生來。
I'll get Mrs. Muller down here with you,
and I'll stay here till the doctor comes.
然後，我們會
帶你去我家。
And then, we'll
take you to my house.
哦，海倫，
這是一種折磨。
Oh, Helen,
it's been such torture.
我是如此愛你。
I love you so.
我不喜歡那位醫生。
I don't like that doctor.
請進去看看
他對我的評價。
Please go in there and find out
what he's saying about me.
親愛的，我會的。
I will, my dear.
他會知道什麼是
跟你有關係，治愈你。
He'll know just what's the
matter with you, and cure you.
現在，別擔心。
Now, don't worry.
現在，斯帕林小姐，幫助我
穿好衣服離開這裡。
Now, Miss Sparling, help me to
get dressed and get out of here.
它再次來到你身邊，
格羅夫納小姐。
It's come over you again,
Miss Grosvenor.
我必須逃脫我被關押在這裡。
你必須幫助我。
I must escape. I'm being held here.
You must help me.
但是你告訴我這些適合的時候
來了，我不是聽。
But you told me when these fits
came on, I wasn't to listen.
我有個朋友。他很有錢。
他會給你錢。
I have a friend. He's rich.
He'll give you money.
現在你又躺下了。
你知道你不能起床。
Now you just lie down again.
You know you mustn't get up.
好吧，如果你不想要錢，
你最想要的是什麼？
Well, if you don't want money,
what do you want most?
他會給你任何東西，如果只是
你會幫我去找他的。
He'll give you anything, if only
you'll help me to go to him.
你想讓我
打電話給穆勒博士？
You want me to
call Dr. Muller?
不，我討厭他。
No. I hate him.
先生，惠普先生？
Mr. Whemple, then?
如果我不離開他，我會死的。
現在，格羅夫納小姐...
I'll die if I don't get away from him.
Now, Miss Grosvenor...
這太痛苦了。你聽到了嗎？
拜託，拜託！
It's killing me. Do you hear?
Please, please!
海倫，你必須
不要再這樣做了。
Now, Helen, you must
not do this again.
你永遠都是這樣
事後筋疲力盡。
You're always so
exhausted afterwards.
她太弱了無法移除，
除了去醫院。
She's too weak to be removed,
except to a hospital.
我堅持讓她留在這裡
根據我們的直接觀察。
I insist on keeping her here
under our direct observation.
但LeBarron博士，你沒有
告訴我們該為她做些什麼。
But Dr. LeBarron, you haven't
told us what to do for her.
她每天都變弱了。
She's getting weaker every day.
你知道那個便服
我在巴黎買？
You know that negligee
I bought in Paris?
幫幫我穿上，
把我的廁所帶給我。
Help me to put it on,
and bring me my toilet things.
我想要一些顏色。
我想好看。
I want some color.
I want to look well.
但親愛的，你不能這樣做。他們會
從不允許它。護士會...
But you can't do that, my dear. They'd
never allow it. The nurse would be...
我知道。
我們會擺脫她
I know.
We'll get rid of her.
這是一個情節，
就在我們之間
This is a plot,
just between us.
我想看看我做的方式。
對法蘭克來說，這真是一個驚喜
I want to look the way I did.
Just a surprise, for Frank.
我希望你把他帶到我身邊。
你明白？
And I want you to bring him to me.
You understand?
總之，我失敗了
做出診斷。
In short, I have failed
to make a diagnosis.
醫學無助
在這種情況下。
Medical science is helpless
in a case like this.
法蘭克
Frank.
去找她，然後
不要生我的氣。
Go to her, and
don't be angry with me.
我無法抗拒她。
I couldn't resist her.
哦，但海倫，你
不應該這樣做。
Oh, but Helen, you
shouldn't have done this.
他們不應該讓你。
They shouldn't have let you.
就這一次。
也許是最後一次。
Just this once.
Perhaps the last time.
但是你會好起來的。
But you're going to get well.
然後我知道我可以
讓你愛我
Then I know I can
make you love me.
我知道我可以讓你快樂。
I know I can make you happy.
法蘭克，我愛你。
而我正在努力證明這一點，
I do love you, Frank.
And I'm trying to prove it,
因為我寧願死
生活，失去你。
because I'd rather die
than live and lose you.
但是你要活著。我們
不會相互失去。
But you're going to live. We're
not going to lose each other.
所以，親愛的...
別罵我。
So, my dear...
Don't scold me.
只是女人味的虛榮心。一世
我想再次看起來最好。
Just feminine vanity. I
wanted to look my best again.
所以你知道的不僅僅是
我意識到你知道。
So you know more than
I realized you knew.
你什麼意思？
What do you mean?
這些衝動要發給他。
These impulses to go to him.
拉力過大
承受和生活。
The pull is too strong
to withstand and live.
我很高興你理解。
I'm so glad you understand.
海倫知道。
Helen knows.
她知道這一刻
她停止掙扎，
She knows the moment
she stops struggling,
他會把她還給她
她有力量來找他。
he will give her back
her strength to come to him.
但我不想
失去了自己的想法
But I don't want to
lose my own mind
並成為別人，
我討厭的人。
and be someone else,
someone I hate.
我親愛的，而你
變得越來越糟
My dear, while you
were growing worse,
我們試圖找到他
並失敗了。
we tried to find him
and failed.
下次打電話
來吧，去找他。
The next time the call
comes, go to him.
穆勒，我們現在能做什麼？
Muller, what can we do now?
我們不能再做了。
阿德斯.貝打敗了我。
We can do no more.
Ardeth has beaten me.
下次他吸引她
對他來說，我們必須跟著她。
The next time he draws her
to him, we must follow her.
然後？
And then?
我們會毀了他。
We will destroy him.
我給了她一些溴化物。她
現在睡著了。我會去睡覺
I've given her some bromide. She's
asleep now. I'll go to bed.
行。我會在這裡等到博士
穆勒來了。
All right. I'll wait here till Dr.
Muller comes.
晚安。
Good night.
我們在哪？
Where are we?
這是我的床，但這不是
寺廟也不是我父親的宮殿。
This is my bed, but this is not the
temple nor my father's palace.
不要看，安克蘇娜姆
Do not look,
Anck-es-en-Amon.
不要害怕。
Do not be afraid.
我很害怕。
I was afraid.
當你跪在我的床邊時，
面紗從我的眼睛里傳來。黑暗
When you were kneeling beside my bed,
a veil came over my eyes. Darkness.
你最後的記憶是我的
在你死亡的那一刻
Your last memory is of me
in the hour of your death
當我跪在你的床邊時，
3，700年前。
as I knelt by your bed,
3,700 years ago.
從來沒有人遭受過任何苦難
女人，因為你為我受苦。
No man has ever suffered for
woman as you suffered for me.
而現在，眾神
原諒我們...
And now that the gods
have forgiven us...
不，不，還沒有。
No, no, not yet.
你的靈魂是一個凡人的身體，
Your soul is in a mortal body,
自那以後多次更新
我們喜歡在舊的底比斯。
renewed many times since
we loved in Thebes of old.
但那種愛不適合我們
再一次，直到偉大的變化。
But that love is not for us
again until the great change.
我不明白。
I do not understand.
看。
Look.
看，想知道。
Look and wonder.
我自己的身影。
Figure of myself.
這是我的棺材，由我的棺材製成
父親反對我的死。
It is my coffin, made by my
father against my death.
什麼木乃伊篡奪了我的
永恆的安息之所？
What mummy has usurped my
eternal resting place?
這是你的死殼。
It is thy dead shell.
我試著提出這個
身體。我現在可以提高它。
I tried then to raise this
body. I could raise it now.
但這只是一件事
在沒有靈魂的情況下，我的意志感動了。
But it would be a mere thing that
moved at my will, without a soul.
這不僅僅是這個身體
我喜歡的。這是你的靈魂。
It was not only this body
that I loved. It was thy soul.
我毀掉了這個沒有生氣的東西。
I destroy this lifeless thing.
你取代它的位置
但是片刻之後
Thou shalt take its place
but for a few moments,
再起來，
即使我已經復活了。
and then rise again,
even as I have risen.
來。
Come.
印和闐，這是
屍體的地方。
Imhotep, this is the
place of embalmment.
這對我來說是不合法的，是女祭司
伊希斯，看到或觸摸一個不潔的東西。
It is not lawful for me, a priestess of
Isis, to see or touch an unclean thing.
來到阿努比斯的祭壇，
死者的嚮導。
Come to the altar of Anubis,
the guide of the dead.
時機已到
為了最後的祈禱。
The time has come
for the final prayers.
我和阿努比斯有什麼關係？
What have I to do with Anubis?
古老的儀式一定是
在你的身體上表演。
The ancient rites must be
performed over thy body.
然後我會讀
偉大的咒語
Then I will read
the great spell
伊希斯帶來的
奧西里斯從墳墓回來。
with which Isis brought
Osiris back from the grave.
你又要復活了。
And thou shalt rise again.
沒有。
No.
不，我還活著！
我年輕！我不會死的！
No, I'm alive!
I'm young! I won't die!
我曾經愛過你，但現在
你屬於死人。
I loved you once, but now
you belong with the dead.
我是安克蘇娜姆，
I am Anck-es-en-Amon,
但是我...我也是其他人。
but I... I'm somebody else, too.
我想生活，即使在
這個奇怪的新世界。
I want to live, even in
this strange new world.
為了你的緣故
我活埋了。
For thy sake
I was buried alive.
我只問你
痛苦的一刻。
I ask of thee only
a moment of agony.
只有這樣我們才能團結起來。
Only so can we be united.
natron浴。
The bath of natron.
你不應該暴跌
我的身體進入那個！
You shall not plunge
my body into that!
讓契約完成。
Let the deed be done.
讓我走！
Let me go!
別殺了我！我是一個
伊希斯的女祭司！
Don't kill me! I'm a
priestess of Isis!
救我脫離那個木乃伊！
它死了！救救我！
Save me from that mummy!
It's dead! Save me!
我不再害怕你了。
和我一起做你想做的事
I no longer fear you.
Do with me what you will.
法蘭克！
Frank!
她去了他。
他們必須在博物館。
She's gone to him.
They must be in the museum.
現在我知道他可怕的計劃。
Now I know his horrible plan.
他會殺了她並製造
她像個自己一樣活著的木乃伊。
He's going to kill her and make
her a living mummy, like himself.
眾神將進入黑社會
安克蘇娜姆的精神。The gods will receive into the underworld
the spirit of Anck-es-en-Amon.
但不長久。
But not for long.
奧西里斯會釋放你的靈魂。
Osiris will release thy soul.
你將從生活中休息，
You shall rest from life,
喜歡夕陽
在西方。
like the setting sun
in the West.
但是你會重新開始
在東方
But you shall dawn anew
in the East
作為第一縷曙光
Amon-Ra驅散陰影。
as the first rays of
Amon-Ra dispel the shadows.
看！那是什麼？
Look! What's that?
來吧！
Come on!
法蘭克！法蘭克！
Frank! Frank!
海倫！
Helen!
哦，伊希斯！神聖的少女！
Oh, Isis! Holy Maiden!
我是你奉獻的外衣。
我打破了我的誓言。救救我吧！
I was thy consecrated vestal.
I broke my vows. Save me now!
教我古老的召喚，
我忘記的神聖咒語。
Teach me the ancient summons,
the holy spells I've forgotten.
我一如既往地叫你！
I call upon thee as of old!
海倫。
Helen.
叫她。他拖了
她回到古埃及。
Call her. He has dragged
her back to Ancient Egypt.
叫她！她的愛
你可能會跨越幾個世紀。
Call her! Her love for
you may bridge the centuries.
海倫。海倫！
Helen. Helen!
回來。
這是法蘭克。
Come back.
It's Frank.
回來
Come back.